Emil Mebasser

Software Engineer

310-633-1049 • eimebasser@gmail.com • Los Angeles, CA • linkedin.com/in/emilmebasser • github.com/eimebasser

SUMMARY

Established Software Engineer/Business development professional with 15+ years of experience, at Fortune 500 companies valued over \$300M, focused on developing full-stack applications in JavaScript(ES6+), React, Node, and Express. Co-creator of dbSpy, an open-source data modeling/visualization tool to build relational databases (dbspy.io).

SKILLS

Javascript (ES6+), TypeScript, React, React Router, Redux, NodeJS, Express, REST API, Webpack, SQL (Postgres), NoSQL (MongoDB), HTML5, CSS3, Version Control (Git/GitHub), OAuth, Proxying, TDD (Jest/Puppeteer/Enzyme/SuperTest), Three.js, Dev Tools API.

Work Experience

OS Labs - Software Engineer

June 2022 - Present

- Used JavaScript to generate dynamic files and executable queries for users to create new databases in 5+SQL query syntaxes.
- Generated schema logic for datasets to curtail redundancies that may have triggered silent errors by 20%.
- Implemented Dark Mode styling via updates to the Typescript and the React/Mantine libraries to enable multiple visual possibilities, reducing eye strain by 30%.
- Refactored styling from inline React components to adhere to CSS best practices in regards to specificity, improving future style
 management as well as simplifying color scheme organization; reduced lines of code by 50%.
- Implemented React Library components to enable a dynamic styling change, enhancing UX and increasing app usability by approximately 25%.
- Amended react-xarrows to enable the end user to easily trace the path of primary and foreign key relationships through the use of contrasting style and coloration, improving compliance with ARIA standards by 30%. This can be viewed on the project's GitHub.
- Engineered a new system for routing PostgreSQL log setting information throughout the program allowing users to display a new
 modeling system and system administrators to review and track log setup while in the earliest stages of design.
- Combined the React Material UI with revamped and unified front-end React product to quickly integrate reusable pre-fabricated components to grant a faster implementation (improvements up to 30% faster) of features during sprints.
- Fostered Scrum/Agile environment to initiate regular feedback on new features while maintaining the ability to create stories and sprints on those features to ensure the timely release of the product weekly.
- dbSpy developed under tech accelerator OSLabs to enhance overall tech advancements through open-source projects.

WWP, Anastasia of Beverly Hills, TOMS, EASTON, Nestle - Global Sales and Operations Manager January 2006 - March 2022

- Authored and customized forecast tools using VBA & SQL Database that displayed proprietary heuristics and polynomial regression models to create forecasts(overhauled forecast accuracy (90% lag 3), resulting in no sales loss while maintaining strengthened inventory levels by \$1M).
- Maintained financial budgeting (\$300M+) using SQL & VBA to ensure clear and accurate data/insights for the C-Level members
 of the company.
- SAP/NetSuite/SalesForce Admin: Maintained the entirety of data and users within SAP/ NetSuite /Sales Force to ensure ERP functionality and usability (user base of 60+ users).

Recent Projects

TrakR (v.1): Visual Job Search Organization Tool

July 2022 - August 2022

- Implemented ReactFlow to better visualize/emphasize connections between different data entities within the SQL database, by
 using a more efficient component library to get the product to market faster (20% improvement in efficiencies).
- Deployed bcrypt to create secure and safe logging-in of multiple 100-100,000+ users' information.
- Created and normalized/stable/predictable a multi-table(10+ tables) SQL database and wrote complex queries to access datasets
 to ensure stability and security.

EDUCATION

- Codesmith Advanced Residency for Full Stack Engineers
- California State University, Northridge BA of Economics

September 2022 June 2006

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Tech Talks Sponsored by Single Sprout: Amazon Web Services: A guide from A to Z
- CS Review Group Host / Instructor

August 2022 June 2022